Guide to the Harry Langhorne papers, 1972-1977
Langhorne, Harry papers, 1972-1977
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Harry Langhorne papers, 1972-1977
7304
Harry Langhorne
5 cubic ft.
Subject files, correspondence, notes, drafts of essays, printed material.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The collection consists of the papers of Harry Langhorne, a Philadelphia area gay activist and executive officer of the Gay Activists Alliance of Philadelphia. Includes subject files relating to all aspects of the gay movement and of other liberal and radical social causes.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Harry Langhorne was an executive administrator of the Gay Activists Alliance of Philadelphia (GAA) from 1972 to 1977.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The collection consists of the subject files kept by Langhorne while at the Gay Activists Alliance (GAA), as well as his correspondence, notes, drafts of essays, and other accumulated printed material. The committees referred to in the files are those of GAA. Topics include gay legal rights and legislation, sodomy laws, gay politics including especially gay Marxism, bi- and transsexuality, gay media concerns, sex education, homophobia, special gay interest groups such as handicapped gays, and gay-church issues. The collection documents relations between CAA and the gay liberation movement and Philadelphia, the State of Pennsylvania, and national political governments, especially pertaining to their statues and practices relating to the gay movement. GAA communications with other regional and national gay organizations and many of their publications are included.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Langhorne, Harry.; Gay Activists Alliance (Philadelphia, Pa.).
Subjects:
Gay men.; Gays--Political action.; Sodomy.; Gay liberation movement.; Gays--Identity.; Sex instruction.; Homophobia.; Homosexuality--Laws and legislation.; Homosexuality.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
The arrangement of the files is alphabetical according to the original folder headings, with a small additional group of miscellaneous and unordered subject files following.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Subject Files
Boxes 1-5
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Subject Files
  - Academy Screening Room (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ACLU (American Civil Liberties Union) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Action Alliance of Senior Citizens (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Advocate (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Affirmative Action (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alcoholism and Gays (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Allentown (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Amazons, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - American Medical Association (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anti-Gay Bills (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Aumiller (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Aversion Therapy (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Baltimore Gay Alliance (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bar Alvah (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bar Association (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bars (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Berwick (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bibliographies (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Bisexuality (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Black Economic Development Conference (Greater Philadelphia) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Black Legislative Caucus (Pennsylvania) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Blackmail (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Black Panthers (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Blade (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Bread and Roses (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Calendar (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - CALM (Custody Action for Lesbian Mothers) (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Campaign 1976 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Canada - National Gay Rights Coalition (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Catholic Church (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Community Alliance of Philadelphia (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Council for Equal Job Opportunity (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Chicago 1972 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Child Abuse (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Children (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Churches (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - City Council (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - City Council Newsletter (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Civil Rights - Endorsements (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Civil Rights - Endorsement Targets (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Clearinghouse (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Coalition Against Police Abuses (Box 1, Folder 44-45)
  - Coalition - Philadelphia Gay (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Columbus Gay Activist (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Commission on Human Relations (Philadelphia) (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Committee for a Gay Rights Bill (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Common Cause (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Common Sense" Philadelphia Action Report (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Community Advocate Unit (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Concerned Citizens for Gay Rights (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Consciousness Raising (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Correspondence (GAA) (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Council for Social Development (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "The Crusader" (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Delaware (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Democrats (local) (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Democrats (national) (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Dignity (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - District Attorney (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Dyketactics! (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Edinboro (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Education (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - EEOC (Equal Employment Opportunity Commission) (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Elections 1974 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Elections 1976 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Endorsements (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Episcopal Diocese of Pennsylvania (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - ERA (Equal Rights Amendment) (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Eromin Center (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Events in Philadelphia (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Farview (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Fellowship Commission (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Fire Safety (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Floyd, Rev. Melvin (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Forums, GAA (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Free University Course (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Full Employment (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Fund-Raising (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Gay Academic Union (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Gay Activists Alliance (GAA) Philadelphia (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - GAA - Papers: Minutes, Notes, Membership Lists (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - GAA - Duplicate (Legal Cases, Homosexuality) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - GAA - Current (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - GAA - Press Releases and Media Coverage (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - GAA Constitutions (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - GAA - "The Gay Alternative" (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - GAA Alternative, "A Gay Manifesto" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Gay Capitalism (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "The Gay Circle" (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Gay Community Services Berks County (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Gay Democratic Caucus (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Gay Groups' Notices, Outside Philadelphia (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - "Gay Health Reports" (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Gay Lobby Day (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Gay Marxists, Includes "Gay Liberator," other newsletters, correspondence, and position papers (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
  - Gay Media Project (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - Gay Newsletters (Miscellaneous), Includes "Chicago Gay Pride CGA Newsletter," "Challenge," "AC/DC Atlantic City," and others (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Gay Nurses Alliance (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Gays of the Northeast (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Gay People in the Labor Force" (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - "Gay People and Mental Health" (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Gay People, Princeton, New Jersey (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "Gay Post" (New York City) (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Gay Pranksters (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Gay Press Association (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Gay Pride 1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Gay Pride Week (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Gay Public Health Workers (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Gay Radio (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Gay Raiders (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Gay Rights Bills (Box 2, Folder 36-38)
  - Gay Rights National Lobby (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Gay Rights Pamphlet (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Gay Rights Platforms, Political Statements (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Gay Social Services Alliance (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Gay South Jersey (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Gay Students at the University of Pennsylvania, Includes Allen Ginsberg Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Gay Students at the University of Pittsburgh (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Gay Students at Temple University (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Gay Switchboard (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Gay Symposium 1975 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Gay United Lancaster (Pennsylvania) (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Gays in Washington, D.C., Includes "Just Us - A Directory of the Washington Gay Community" (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Gay and Women's Alliance for Responsible Media - "GWARM Monitor" (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Gay Youth - "GY Gay Youth's Gay Journal" (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - "Gayzette" (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - "Gayellow Pages" (1976) (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Government Printing Office (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Gray, Bill (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Grey Panthers (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - GM and Exec., Typewritten and handwritten minutes and notes (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - H Miscellaneous, Statement by Harry Langhorne before the regional Democratic Platform Committee Hearing, 3 June 1972; also National Gay Community for McGovern (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Homophile Action League (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Harrisburg Conference 1975 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Handicapped Gays, Committee for (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Health and Safety, Committee on (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Henri David (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "HERA - A Philadelphia Feminist Publication" (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Homophile Union of Boston (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - "Homosexual Counseling Journal" (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - HOPS, "Zap!" From the State College Gay Community (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Horn, Stu (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - HOW Newsletters: "Here's HOW" (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Housing Authority of Delaware Valley (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Human Relations Commission, Pennsylvania (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - International Women's Year (IWY) (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Incorporation (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Immigration and Naturalization (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Integrity/Philadelphia (Gay Episcopalians and their Friends) (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Jews (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - July 4th Coalition (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Journal (Harry Langhorne) (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Lambda Legal Defense Fund (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - La Salle College Students for Individual Rights (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Lauritsen, John, Includes article on "snuff" film, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Lavender and Red Union, "Come Out Fighting," the Newspaper of the LRU (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Liquor Control Board, Pennsylvania (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - "Le-Hi-Ho News", Lehigh Valley Homophile Organization (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Legal Matters (Box 3, Folder 8-9)
  - Legal Miscellaneous, Society for Individual Rights Pocket Lawyer; "If You Are Arrested" (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Legislative Committee (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Lesbian Mothers (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Los Angeles Gay Community Center (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "Marcus Welby, M.D." (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - George McGovern (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Maps (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Men Against Patriarchy (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Men's Liberation (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Merry-Go-Round (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Methodists (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Metropolitan Community Church (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Fellowship of Metropolitan Community Churches - Washington (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Miami (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Millersville State College (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Mr. Livingroom (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Movies (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - NAACP (National Association for the Advancement of Colored People) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - National Coalition of Gay Activists (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - National Coalition of Gay Organizations, Democratic National Convention, Miami, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - National Gay Rights (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - National Gay Student Center (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - National Gay Task Force (Box 3, Folder 33-35)
  - National Lawyers Guild (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - National Organization for Women (NOW) (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - NEPGA (Northeastern Pennsylvania Gay Alliance) (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - "New American Movement" (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - New Democratic Coalition of Pennsylvania (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - New Democratic Party of Canada (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 3, Folder 43-46)
  - Newspaper Editorials (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - One (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Operation Fightback (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Pennsylvania, Gay Rights Advisory Committee, Governors's Council for Sexual Minorities, and other legal matters (Box 3, Folder 50-51)
  - Pennsylvania Commission on Gay Rights (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Pennsylvania Commission on Sexual Minorities (Box 3, Folder 53-54)
  - Pennsylvania Council for Sexual Minorities (Box 3, Folder 55-59)
  - P.M.C. (Philadelphians [Motorcycle Club?])"Scribe's Newsletter" (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Pennsylvania State Education Association (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Pennsylvanians for Women's Rights (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - People's Business (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - People's Fund (Box 3, Folder 64-65)
  - People's Party (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Petition (Harrisburg) (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Petition (Philadelphia) (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Philadelphia (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Philadelphia Civil Service Regulations (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Philadelphia Gay Community Center (Box 4, Folder 8-11)
  - Philadelphia Gay Conference (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - "Philadelphia Gay News" (PGN) II, Langhorne draft manuscripts of articles; discussion of Walt Whitman (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - PGN December, Langhorne draft manuscripts (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - PGN August (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - PGN Index (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - PGN Advertising (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - PGN January 1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - PGN Interviews (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - "Philadelphia Magazine" (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Philadelphia Party (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Philadelphia Urban Coalition (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - "Pittsburgh Gay News" (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Pittsburgh State Conference (Pennsylvania State Gay Convention) (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Planned Parenthood (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Police (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Police and Corrections (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Police Commission (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Polls (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Pornography (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Presbytery (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Press (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Presstype (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Prison (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Privacy (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Propaganda Committee (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Psychiatry (Box 4, Folder 32-33)
  - Quakers (Box 4, Folder 35-36)
  - Questionnaire (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Racism (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - "Radical Queen" (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "Recon" (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Religion (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
  - Research (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Rights Legislation (Box 4, Folder 43-44)
  - Rinear, Chuck (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Ripon Society (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Rittenhouse Square (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Rizzo (Citizens' Committee to Recall Rizzo) (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Roommate File (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Rural Caucus (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Rutgers University Homophile League (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - S-1 (Federal) (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - S-M Committee (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - San Francisco Association for Mental Health (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Schapp (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Seattle (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Segal, Mark (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Senate Bill No. 83, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - "Sexual Law Reporter" (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Sex Education (Box 4, Folder 59-64)
  - SIECUS (Sex Information and Education Council of the United States) (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - SIR (Society for Individual Rights - San Francisco) (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Sodomy (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - "Solidarity Newsletter" (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Songs (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Speakers Bureau (Gay) (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Social committee (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Socialists Workers Party (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - State (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - State (Gay Task Force, Council for Sexual Minorities) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - State Legislators (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - State - Gay Civil Rights Bill, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - State Party Platforms (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Stationery (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Stonewall - Seattle; Gay Community Services, Minnesota (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sunshine Law (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Super Sunday - 1976 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Susan Saxe Case (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - TLA Cinema (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Television (Box 5, Folder 23-25)
  - Tax (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Telephone (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Time Magazine (Matlovich) (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Transsexuals (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Transvestites, including "Journal of Male Feminism" v. 77, no. 2 and National Alliance for Heterosexual Male Feminism items. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Treasurer (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Philadelphia Tribune (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Twenty Questions (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Universal Church of Jesus Christ (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Unions (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
  - United States Civil Service Commission (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - "Vanguard Vanities", Vanguard Motor Club of Philadelphia, founded 1969 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - "Vector" (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Venereal Disease (Box 5, Folder 40-41)
  - Villanova University (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Voter Registration (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - White, Ralph (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - "Wicce" (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Women's Action Alliance (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Women's Committee (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Women's Political Caucus (Box 5, Folder 50-51)
  - Women's Rights (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Women's Switchboard (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - WPVI - Channel 6 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - WUHY Radio ("Rest of the News" Brochure) (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Young Lords (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Youth Against War and Fascism (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Youth Services Commission (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Youth Studies Center (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous Non-alphabetized files
  - Miscellaneous Articles (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Philadelphians for Gay Rights (PGR) (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Bank Statements (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Clippings (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Harry Langhorne Writings, Notes, lists, drafts of letters and essays (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence, Letters to GAA (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - GAA - Materials Prepared for Presentation to the People's Fund (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material (Box 5, Folder 65-66)
  - "The Lavender and Red Book" (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - "Sports and the Macho Male" (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - "Achilles Heel" (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - "Religious Roots of the Taboo on Homosexuality" (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - "Report of the Pennsylvania Council for Sexual Minorities" (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - "Gay Oppression and Liberation" (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - "Gays on Campus" (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - "Gay Left" (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - "Outcome" (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - "Greater Philadelphia Publicity Guide 1975" (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - "College English" (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Pamphlets, Gay (Box 5, Folder 78)